Mo... ther.
母亲
Wait.
等等
Please wait, Shinichi. You have it wrong.
请等一下 真一 你一定弄错了
What am I wrong about, Sumi?
我弄错什么了 澄美?
About Miyo...
美世她...
No supernatural abilities.
没有异能
She's not showing any signs of them at all.
甚至没有一点迹象
Please don't give up on Miyo.
请不要舍弃美世
If we were a mediocre family without supernatural abilities,
如果我们家是没有异能的平凡之家
perhaps I could have loved Miyo.
我肯定会爱美世的
I'm sorry, Miyo.
对不起 美世
Since I don't have much time left, I will not be able to protect you.
我已经没有多少时间了 不能保护你
But I have no doubt you'll be all right.
不过没有问题的
Once you grow up a little bit more, then...
只要你再长大一些...
Mother...
母亲...
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
剧名:我的幸福婚约
EPISODE 4 THE GIFT
第4集:赠送之物
Ms. Yurie.
由里江阿姨
Is anything the matter, Ms. Miyo?
怎么了 美世小姐?
Um, may I ask you something, Ms. Yurie?
我有事想问您
Certainly.
你想问什么?
Actually, I wanted to give a gift
其实我想
to my husband-to-be.
送礼物给老爷
Oh my!
天啊
Um, shouldn't I do the dishes?
请问 那些碗怎么办?
Don't worry about that now.
现在不用担心这些了
It's more important to think about what to give to the Young Master.
眼下最重要的是想想要送什么给少爷
I only have a very small budget.
我没有多少钱
I don't know if I can buy a gift he would like.
我不知道老爷能否喜欢我的礼物
You won't need to buy anything expensive if you can make him something by hand.
不必买什么高价物品 你亲手做的东西就可以
Something by hand?
“亲手做的东西”?
Yes.
对
How about something he uses daily?
少爷平日里会用到的东西如何?
He would surely love anything you make by hand, Ms. Miyo.
不论你做的是什么 他应该都会喜欢
Do you... think so?
真的吗?
Yes.
当然
Me making something by hand...
我亲手做的东西
That's a nice kumihimo cord.
很漂亮的编绳啊
It's pretty.
好美
I think... I'd like to make this.
我要做这个
Um, sir?
老爷 请问
What is it?
什么?
Would it be alright if I went out for a while today?
我今天可以出门一阵吗?
Why?
怎么了?
Well, there's something I want to buy.
我想买点东西
Are you going alone?
你一个人去吗?
No, with Ms. Yurie.
不 我和由里江阿姨一起去
I could accompany you on another day.
过几天 我和你一起去也行
No, there's no need for that.
不 不麻烦您了
I see.
这样啊
Be careful when you go out.
出门小心
Don't follow strangers.
不要跟着陌生人走了
Yes, sir.
好的
Also,
以及
take this with you when you go out.
出门时带着这个
What's this?
这个是什么?
It's an amulet.
是护身符
Oh, thank you very much.
谢谢您
You must keep it with you at all times, understood?
你要一直带在身上
Y-Yes, sir.
好的
Do you really understand?
你真的明白吗?
O-Of course I do.
当然了
I'm going now.
我出门了
Have a nice day.
路上小心
He gave me an amulet just for going out.
老爷给了我护身符
He's being overprotective.
真是小题大做了
Mr. Koji.
幸次少爷
Ms. Kaya has arrived.
香耶小姐来了
If you show up with a disgruntled expression like that,
表情如此乏味的话
your fiancée will become upset.
你的未婚妻会很生气的
Big brother! What are you doing here?
兄长 你为什么会在这里?
It must be hard sucking up to Kaya Saimori.
要讨好斋森香耶可不容易吧
I'm not enjoying it.
我又不是因为喜欢才做的
I'm impressed as always, Koji, with you being dutiful and obedient.
你还真是一点没变呢 守规矩又正直的幸次同学
This is what I have to endure because you're always playing around.
这都是因为你一直在玩 我才会这么辛苦
Why don't you stop goofing off and act more like the eldest--
不要游手好闲了 表现得像个长子如何...
You're too kind, which makes you unkind.
你就是因为太温柔了 对人才一点都不好
What the hell...
这算什么啊
Wow!
好棒啊
There's so many to choose from.
真是让人眼花缭乱
I wonder what color will look good on him?
衬得起老爷的颜色是哪个呢?
This might suit him.
这个或许很合适他
Thank you very much.
多谢惠顾
I'm glad you found a good color.
能找到这么好的颜色真是太好了
Yes. I'm looking forward to braiding it.
是 我很期待将它编制成型
Oh, I just remembered.
对了 我想起来了
We are out of salt.
食盐用光了
Should I go buy some?
我去买吧?
No, no. It's my job to buy salt.
不 这是我的工作
Please wait for me here, Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐 请在此稍等片刻
Oh! Isn't that Big Sister?
这不是姐姐吗?
Kaya...
香耶
It's been a long time, Big Sister Miyo.
好久不见 美世姐姐
We've been waiting for you,
久候多时了
Mr. Kudo.
久堂阁下
Thank you for welcoming me on such short notice.
我突然拜访 感谢你们的欢迎
We're honored that you came here in spite of your busy schedule.
您在百忙之中莅临寒舍 是我们的荣幸
So, what brings you here today?
那么今天您有何贵干?
It's about your daughter, Miyo.
是关于您的女儿 美世
Miyo? What about Miyo?
美世?那孩子做了什么?
I'm planning to officially get engaged
我打算正式和她缔结婚约
and marry her in the future.
并于近日完婚
I... see.
这样啊
Therefore,
正因如此
I feel that we should make clear the relationship between our families.
必须厘清我们两家的关系
What do you mean by relationship?
关系是指什么呢?
Ordinarily, marriages of our kind are established according to mutual interests.
本来像我们这样的人的婚姻 是与彼此的利害关系相关
However,
但是我
I feel hesitant to giving anything to your family with this marriage.
不想因为这桩婚事与你们扯上关系
What are you...
你是说...
Don't you realize?
还不明白吗?
I know what you did to Miyo.
你对美世的所作所为
I know practically all of it.
我全都知道了
How surprising that you're still alive, Big Sister.
天啊 姐姐你还活着 真是让人意外
Oh, but...
只不过
since you're still wearing those undignified clothes,
你的穿着还是这么不得体
Mr. Kudo must have abandoned you.
肯定是被久堂大人抛弃了吧?
Poor Big Sister.
真是可怜
I... I wasn't...
我不是...
Stop it, Kaya.
香耶 不要这样
Well,
不过
I guess it couldn't be helped.
这也是无可奈何的
There's no way a good-for-nothing like you would be matched with someone like him.
一无是处的你和久堂大人根本不般配
It's only natural you were thrown out of the house.
就算你被赶出家门也不奇怪
You should feel lucky you're still alive.
能活着就已经是很幸运的了
That's enough. Let's go, Kaya.
够了 走吧 香耶
Keep quiet, Koji.
你不要说话
You experienced things that made you wish you were dead, didn't you?
你一定已经体会过那种 生不如死的生活了吧
Although I can't even imagine what that was like.
不过我想象不出来
I will pay you the betrothal money, but only under one condition.
我可以付你礼金 不过我有要求
Give Miyo an earnest apology, face to face.
真心实意地对美世当面道歉
Apologize?
道歉?
I won't force you if you don't want to.
我不会强迫你去做
We'll just cut ties with you in that case.
这样一来 我们就此断绝关系就好
If you need money, just ask.
如果你需要钱 张口就好
If you get down on your knees and beg, I'll see what I can do.
只要你跪地请求 我会考虑的
You're being silent like that... It takes me back.
你沉默的样子真让人怀念
Wherever you go, you never change, Big Sister.
不管去哪里 姐姐你都是一成不变呢
I... I'm very... sorry--
非常抱歉
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
Pardon me for keeping you waiting.
让您久等了
Are they acquaintances of yours?
他们是您的熟人吗?
Hello.
你好
My name is Kaya Saimori.
我是斋森香耶
I appreciate you helping my big sister.
家姐多受您的照顾
Are you one of her fellow workers?
您是家姐的同事吗?
I couldn't possibly be a fellow worker of Ms. Miyo.
我怎么担得起美世小姐同事的称呼
Ms. Miyo is the future wife of Mr. Kiyoka Kudo.
美世小姐是久堂清霞大人未来的妻子
Future... wife?
你说“妻子”?
Yes.
是的
Excuse me for not introducing myself. My name is Yurie.
我还没自我介绍 我是由里江
I work as a maid for Ms. Miyo.
我是听命于美世小姐的女仆
Oh my goodness. Mr. Kudo is a kind man, or a rare kind of man.
天啊 久堂大人真是体贴 或是说独特
I was convinced that he had let her go.
我还以为抛弃她了呢
Rumors are not reliable, are they?
流言蜚语不能当真
Well then, if you would excuse us,
我们接下来还有事
we have other errands to do.
就此告辞
Let's go home, Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐 我们回去吧
An apology...
道歉...
Can you give us a little time to think about it?
请允许我们考虑一下
Understood.
我明白了
But I won't wait too long.
不过我不会等很久
Ms. Miyo,
美世小姐
I'll prepare some tea presently.
我马上去泡茶
No thank you, I'm fine.
没关系 我没事的
Ms. Miyo?
美世小姐?
Thank you for coming with me today.
今天谢谢您陪我
You should rest now too, Ms. Yurie.
由里江阿姨也请休息吧
I hate it...
好讨厌
I hate myself for being this way.
我好讨厌这样的自己
How could he be satisfied with a wife like her?
竟然满足于姐姐那样的人做妻子吗?
I think Mr. Kudo is very strange.
久堂大人也真是奇怪
Did we have company?
有客人来吗?
What a beautiful man.
好美的人
I'm home.
我回来了
Welcome home, sir.
欢迎回家
What's the matter?
发生什么事了吗?
Nothing.
不
Nothing in particular.
没什么特别的事
When meeting her sister from the Saimori family,
我们碰到了斋森家的小姐
Ms. Miyo looked very distressed.
美世小姐的脸色变得非常痛苦
She's just been moping since we came home.
回来之后就一直在擦地板
I'm sorry this happened on my watch.
我跟着她还发生了这种事 非常抱歉
I see.
我知道了
It's me. Can I talk to you for a minute?
是我 现在方便吗?
Just remember this one thing.
只有一件事
What's worrying you now is not going to matter after a while.
你的烦恼不久之后就会烟消云散
So don't take it so seriously.
所以不用想那么多
If there's anything you want to say to me,
如果你有话对我说
I'm always here to listen.
我随时恭候
I'm... very sorry, sir.
对不起
What can I do to give her some confidence?
我要怎么做才能让她拥有自信呢?
The answer is simple, Young Master.
这不是显而易见的吗 少爷?
A woman builds confidence by being loved.
女人要被爱才会拥有自信
Being loved...
被爱吗?
It's not that difficult.
不必想得太复杂
All you have to do is express to her just how much you care about her.
少爷只需要把自己如何珍视美世小姐 这件事传达给她就好
If you engage with her sincerely with all your heart,
诚实地 饱含真心地与之相对
she will certainly understand how you feel.
她肯定会明白你的心意的
I'm done braiding the kumihimo cord,
编绳已经做完了
but I could never give it to him now.
但是我却不能送给老爷
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
May I open the door?
您现在方便吗?
Yes. Come in.
请进
You have company.
您有客人
It's really been a long time, Ms. Miyo.
好久不见 美世大小姐
Hana!
花
I'm glad to see you're doing well.
看见您过得不错真是太好了
You too, Hana.
你也是
I'm so happy to see you're well.
还和以前一样 我很开心
I got married.
我结婚了
And I have a child now.
还生了一个孩子
I live a modest, happy life.
虽然微不足道 我过得很幸福
That's wonderful.
太好了
For a long time, I've wanted to see you happy and smiling.
我一直希望您幸福地欢笑
From that day...
那天之后
when I was forbidden to be beside you, I lived at my family home.
自从不能伴您左右后 我回到了老家
Are you happy now, Ms. Miyo?
您现在幸福吗?
I don't deserve it...
我不配获得幸福
Because...
因为
I don't have supernatural abilities.
我没有异能
Not even Spirit-Sight.
甚至不能见鬼
So I don't deserve to be his wife...
我不配做老爷的妻子
I don't deserve to be happy!
我不配拥有幸福
Do you know how I was brought here to meet you?
大小姐 您知道 我是怎么得以来这看您的吗?
The first time I received a letter from him, I was very surprised.
我收到来信的时候非常吃惊
To me, he lives in another world.
对于我来说 他是云端上的人
Ms. Miyo,
美世小姐
Mr. Kudo is a good man, isn't he?
久堂大人是很好的人
TO HANA KANAO
(致 金尾花)
Sir?
老爷?
Why?
为什么?
Did he already know everything?
他全都知道了吗?
I thought I wasn't worthy because I don't have supernatural abilities,
我以为我不像香耶 没有见鬼之才 也没有异能
unlike Kaya.
是毫无价值的
I was scared to lose my happiness by revealing this fact to him.
我害怕如果对老爷和盘托出 我就会失去现在的幸福
I was sure that if he found out the truth, I would be abandoned.
我以为如果他知道了真相就会抛弃我
I thought my happiness would disappear.
幸福也会就此消失
I... I was stuck with my assumptions.
我一个人擅作主张
Ms. Miyo, Mr. Kudo wrote me a letter to help you
大小姐 久堂大人知道了一切
while fully aware of your situation.
还为了你写信给我
So all you have to do is have a little bit of courage.
所以你只要拿出一点勇气就够了
It's all right. I know you are capable.
没关系 你可以做到的
Thank you, Hana.
谢谢你 花
I'll try... I'll give it my best.
我会努力的
Sir.
老爷
What is it, so suddenly?
怎么了?突然找我
There's something I... couldn't tell you this whole time.
我一直有事没对您说
I don't have...
我没有
supernatural abilities.
异能
I don't have Spirit-Sight.
也没有见鬼之才
At home, I was working as a servant.
在家里一直被当成仆人对待
I'm not capable of doing what a girl from a noble family is expected to do.
名门之女会做的事我都不会
I purposely kept this fact from you
我觉得很羞愧
because of my shame.
因此隐瞒了这些
If you tell me to die, I'll die.
如果您让我以死谢罪 我会照做的
If you tell me to leave here, I'll leave.
如果您让我离开这个家 我会离开
I'll do so right away.
我会立刻照做的
I wanted to thank you for going into town with me, giving me a comb,
您陪我出门 送我梳子
and so many other things I'm grateful for.
我要感谢您的事非常多
I made this myself to express my gratitude.
我怀着感激的心情做了这个
I don't mind if you discard or burn it if you don't need it.
您要扔掉或是烧掉也没关系
Now I've told you everything that I needed to say.
这就是我全部要说的
Will you please tell me your decision, sir?
老爷 能告诉我您的决断吗?
How long are you going to do that?
你打算那样跪多久?
I need you to stay with me,
你要是走了我会很头疼的
because soon, we're going to get formally engaged.
再过几天 我打算和你正式订婚
Don't you want to keep living here with me?
你不喜欢和我住在一起吗?
I...
我...
I do... I want to stay here,
我想留在这里
with your permission, sir.
如果您允许的话
Permission?
说什么允不允许
I'm the one who wants you to be here.
我想要你留在这里
Nobody but me.
不是别人 是你
S-Sir.
老爷
Sorry.
抱歉
It's all right.
没关系
It's a beautiful color.
很漂亮的颜色
Miyo, would you tie my hair with this?
你能为我扎起来吗?
Yes.
好
It's done.
弄好了
Thank you. I'll use it with care.
谢谢你 我会珍惜的
Hana.
花
Thank you so, so much.
真的谢谢你
If I hadn't met you...
如果没有遇见你
If you hadn't said those words to me...
如果没有你对我说的那些话
I would still be sitting alone in my room.
我会一直窝在房间里
I'm honored to have been of help. I'm glad we could talk, too.
能帮得上忙是我的荣幸 我也很高兴能和你聊天
Goodbye.
再见
Godo, take good care of her.
五道 交给你了
Yes, sir.
明白
Mr. Kudo.
久堂大人
Thank you very much for inviting me today.
多谢您今天邀请我
Ms. Miyo, I wish you much happiness.
美世小姐一定要幸福
Don't worry.
不用担心
You'll be able to see her any time.
以后随时都能见
Sir.
老爷
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
Don't mention it.
不必道谢
Miyo is getting along well with Kudo?
美世和久堂相处得很好?
We must do something fast in order to make her ours.
要把美世弄到手必须尽快动手
But what?
但是要怎么做?
I know.
我知道了
That girl is the answer.
那个女孩
She'll dance for us like a puppet on a string.
应该能上演一出好戏